Guilderland Central Teachers' Association; Records apap302
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Guilderland Central Teachers' Association Records
1968-1999
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Guilderland Central Teachers' Association (N.Y.)
apap302
2.0 cubic ft.
These records document the day-to-day activities of the Guilderland (N.Y.) Central Teachers' Association.
Collection X
Biographical History
The Guilderland Central Teachers' Association is a local of the American Federation of Teachers with offices in Schenectady, NY. Its members teach in the Guilderland Central School District.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes contracts, correspondence, salary information, pay grade information, and administrative files from the Guilderland Central Teachers' Association. Also included in the collection are negotiations between the Guilderland Central Teachers' Association and its schools, as well as meeting minutes from various meetings held by the Association. The collection also features a seal maker for the Association.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Acquisition Information
Steve Zahurak donated the collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2008 April.
Access
The majority of this collection is unrestricted. Select files noted on the finding aid are restricted. In addition, two folders are closed for 75 years from the date the materials were created because of attorney-client privilege. One folder is closed until 2061 and the other is closed until 2066.
Education; Labor unions--New York (State); Teachers' unions--New York (State); Collective bargaining--New York (State); Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Collective labor agreements; Guilderland Central School District (N.Y.); Guilderland Central Teachers' Association (N.Y.)
- 1987 Guilderland Central School District Proposals (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1987 Guilderland Central School District Proposals (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1992 New York State Retirement Incentive Bill, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1995-1996 School District Profile
- Administrative/ Supervisory Plan and Negotiations, 1988; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Affinities, Volume 1, Number 4, Fall, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agenda for Regular Meeting of the Board of Education- August 25, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreements Between the Board of Education Guilderland Central School District and the Guilderland Central Teachers Association, 1968; 1975; 1983; 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Agreements Between the Board of Education Guilderland Central School District and the Guilderland Central Teachers Association, 1989; 1992; 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Agreement Between North Colonies Central School District and North Colonies Teachers' Association from June 1, 1985- June 30, 1989, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agreement Between the Superintendent of Schools and the Faculty Association of the Cambridge Central School, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Area's Largest Credit Unions, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Areas of Tentative Agreement, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bargaining Update Agenda, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Basic School District Information for Use at 1987 Representative Assembly, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Behavioral Theories of Negotiations and Their Relation to Public Employee Bargaining- J. Donald Herring, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Budget Analysis, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Budget Detail by Function, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Budget and Financial Report, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Budget in the News, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Capital Area School Development Association Statistical and Financial Study of CASDA Schools, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- CASDA Action- Statistical and Financial Study of CASDA Schools, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Clause for Distribution of Excellence in Teaching (EIT) Funds, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Coaching Salaries, 1990; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Contracts, 1987-1988; Undated (Flat-file 1)
- Crisis in American Education, Originally Published in 1947, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- District Contract Issues, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- District Proposal and GTA's Counter Proposals Final Contracts (1 of 2), 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- District Proposal and GTA's Counter Proposals Final Contracts (2 of 2), 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- District Proposals and Negotiations, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- District's Illustration of Compaction, Undated (Flat-file 2)
- Do More With Less Budget, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Draft of Planning Meeting February 26, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- East Greenbush Central Schools Proposed School Calendar, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- East Greenbush TA Contract- September 9, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Elected Board Members, 1990; 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Elementary Teacher Planning Time, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Employee Payrolls, 1985-1989; 1992; 1994-1995; 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Farnsworth Middle School - End of the Year Program Evaluation, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Farnsworth Middle School - Foreign Language Enrollments - March 1, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- General Notes, 1985; 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Greenwich- Memorandum of Agreement, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Grievance - RESTRICTED, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Must consult an archivist before viewing this material.
- Ground Rules for Negotiation- February 15, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- GTA/ GSD Planning Teams and Meeting Schedules, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Guidelines and Procedures for Teachers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Guilderland Central School Budget, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Guilderland Contract Revisions- November 18 Teachers Association, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Guilderland Nurses- New Yoke State Division of Human Rights, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Guilderland Teachers Association Negotiations, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Guilderland Teachers Association in the News, 1985; 1992; 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Guilderland's Teachers Association Proposals for Intensive Bargaining- June 3-4, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Handbook of Benefits and Related Procedures for Distinct Wide Professional Administrative Personal, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Health Care Information for Referees, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Health Insurance Program, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Highlights of Tentative Agreements, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Hiring Practices, 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Identifiable Differences Between GCSD #0 and GTA #11, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Impeach Pataki Sticker, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Improvements for Teachers in the Classroom - February 23, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Information Bulletins, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Local Early Retirement Incentive, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Local Leaders' Guide to Search and Educational Services, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Longevity, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Mandatory/ Non- Mandatory Subject of Negotiation- October, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Median Salaries for EIT, Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Meeting Comments, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Member Benefit Plans, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Membership Dues- Rebate Information - August 20, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Memorandum, Agreement Between Superintendent of the Berne- Knox- Westerlo Central School District and the Berne- Knox- Westerlo Teachers Association- July 1, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Memorandum of Agreement by and Between South Colonie Central School District and South Colonie Teachers Association for 1998-2003, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Merit Step Advancement for the Those Hired at Step 10- June 6, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Merrimack Films, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Minimum Requirements for Schools in New York State, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Negotiations, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Negotiation Committee Report- June 4, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Negotiations Preparation, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- New York State Mentor Teacher Internship Program- June, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- New York State Penal Code - Section 35.10, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- New York State Unite Teachers- Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Opening Day Meeting, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Outline for the Memorandum Agreement, 1989 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Parent Response to Work Rule Action, 1985 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Pertinent Provisions of the Saratoga Teachers Association, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Presented Data on Sabbaticals and Guidance/Staff Ratio, 1987 March 30-31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Proceedings, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Professional Agreement between Skaneateles Teachers' Association and Skaneateles Central School District, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Professional and Personal Liability Coverage for the Nursing Profession, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Professional Improvement, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Proposal for Additional High School Counselor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Proposals for Contract Negotiations, 1985; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Proposed Contractual Changes - Bargaining Team, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ranking of 12 Capital District Schools by Salary for the 1986-1987 School Year (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Ranking Within the Entire Albany Regional Office Area, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Ranking Worksheet, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Reading Skills Continuum, 1974 September (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Recommendation of the Joint Committee Teacher Evaluation Program, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Registered Nurse Salaries, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Report on NYSUT ED #10 Rensselaerville Conference on Joint Action for Unidentified Bargaining, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Representative Council Meetings - Negotiations, 1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Salary Acceptance, 1972-1973; 1977-1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Salary Changes, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Salary Negotiations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Salary Data, 1992 January (Floppy-disk 1)
- Salary Pay Grades, 1986-1987; Undated (Flat-file 3)
- Salary Rate Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Salary Schedules and Raises, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Scattergram Update, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- School District and Community Special Information Packet, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- School District Information including Census Data and Community Information, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- School District Salary Steps, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- School Enrollment, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Seal, Undated (Oversized 1)
- Seniority Lists, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Statistical and Financial Study, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- State Aid and Suburban Council Schools Salary Levels for 1985-1986, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Status Summary - Negotiations, GCSD and GTA, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Step to Level Salary Advancement, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Suburban Council Pay Grades, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Suburban Council Settlements, 1995; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Suburban Council Step Rankings, 1985-1987; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Suggestions on Some Negotiable Articles, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- A Summary of 1991-1992 Faculty and Salary Stats, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Summer School, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Survey of Suburban Council Staffing, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Syracuse TA Release Time Provision, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Tax Value Data, 1986 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Teacher Salaries, 1986-1987; 1997-1998; Undated (Flat-file 4)
- Teachers Early Retirement, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Teacher's Manual, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Tentative School Calendar for 1989-1989 and 1989-1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Working Together: The Collaborative Style of Bargaining by Stuart Smith, Diana Ball, and Demetri Liontos, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)